

WEB DEVELOPER

Details

9096841552 scot.itakura@gmail.com

Links

LinkedIn

Portfolio

GitHub

Skills

React

HTML5

CSS3

JavaScript

Python / SciPy

MATLAB

ArcGIS

Microsoft Excel

Profile

Web developer leveraging a background in geophysical data analytics and scientific coding programs to design and create unique, memorable, and dependable websites. Earth Science graduate from UC Santa Cruz and certificated Full-Stack Web Developer from UC Berkeley who is enthusiastic to enhance the quality of web applications by employing web development experience, analytical programming education, and passion to design, create, and innovate. Known as a strong team member for their ideas, efficiency, and congenial work atmosphere.

Projects

QualiTrees | Corporate Website, https://qualitrees-503dd.web.app/

Freelance solo project built with React for a start-up business to display products, information about the business, ways to contact, and frequently asked questions. Deployed with Firebase.

Garage Collage, https://garage-collage-2468.herokuapp.com/

Held full responsibility for the front end of a three person group project. Built and created with React and styled using Styled Components, a fully functional garage sale e-commerce website was deployed with Heroku and completed within two weeks.

Employment History

Information Technology Coordinator & Program Instructor, Ability Now Bay Area, Oakland, CA

JANUARY 2020 - PRESENT

IT Coordinator facilitating education to staff on computer, internet, hardware, software, and Zoom needs as well as program instructor.

Staff Engineer, Berlogar Stevens & Associates, Pleasanton, CA

JULY 2019 - JANUARY 2020

Provide support to Project Managers through various tasks associated with subsurface exploration including laboratory testing, construction monitoring and testing services during mass grading, foundation preparation, pile installation, tie back installation, etc.

Geotechnical Engineering Technician, Cornerstone Earth Group Inc., Sunnyvale, CA

SEPTEMBER 2018 - JULY 2020

Conduct geotechnical site observations of earthwork, utility backfill, drainage improvements, excavations, and foundation construction.

Education

Full-Stack Web Development Certificate, University of California, Berkeley, Berkeley, CA

JUNE 2020 - NOVEMBER 2020

Completed a 6 month course in full-stack web development earning a certificate.

Earth Science, Bachelor of Science, University of California, Santa Cruz, Santa Cruz, CA

2014 - 2018

Concentrated in geophysical data analytics and scientific programming with a capstone in practical geophysics.